Guide to the Bettina Bergery Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Bettina Bergery papers
1900-1990
1940-1980
GEN MSS 844
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
25.43
(66 boxes) + 3 art, 2 record album storage
The Bettina Bergery Papers consist of 122 volumes of diaries, 1940-1980; a small amount of other autobiographical writings and writings about fashion design; correspondence with family and friends; scrapbooks, clippings, and other printed material relating to her interests in fashion, art, and politics; photographs and photograph albums relating to the Shaw Jones family, Bergery's friendships, travel in French Equatorial Africa, and diplomatic travels with Gaston Bergery; biographical material, legal documents, and other personal papers; and a small amount of drawings, other visual materials, and objects. Most materials date from circa 1920s-1990s and concern Bergery's life in Paris, fashion design, and her social circle. Some materials relating to her childhood and family in the United States are also present. Research strengths include 20th-century French fashion design; 20th-century European art, literature, and politics; and Gaston Bergery's diplomatic career in Vichy France.
Bergery, Bettina, 1902-1993
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mary M. Thacher, 2002-2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
70-71 (Record album storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Bettina Bergery (1902-1993)
Bettina Bergery was born Elisabeth Shaw Jones on July 20, 1902, in New York City. In 1927 she settled in Paris, where she worked for fashion designers Elsa Schiaparelli, Jeanne Lanvin, and Alix Grès. In 1934 she married Gaston Bergery (1892-1974), French lawyer and member of the Chambre des députés for Seine-et-Oise, Parti républicain radical et radical-socialiste, 1928-1934, and Parti frontiste, 1936-1942. During World War II, Bettina accompanied Gaston on his appointments as ambassador of Vichy France to the Soviet Union (1941) and Turkey (1941-1945). At the end of the war, they returned to France, where Gaston was tried and acquitted by the Haute Cour de justice. Bettina Bergery continued her involvement with fashion design. Her social circle included friendships with aristocrats, fashion designers, artists, and literary figures such as Natalie Barney, Mona von Bismarck, Jean Cocteau, Salvador Dali, Daisy Fellowes, Pope John XXIII, Alain de La Falaise, Marie Laure, Martha Gellhorn, and members of the Mdivani and von Papen families. Bettina Bergery died in Paris on August 14, 1993.
Scope and Contents
The Bettina Bergery Papers consist of 122 volumes of diaries, 1940-1980; a small amount of other autobiographical writings and writings about fashion design; correspondence with family and friends; scrapbooks, clippings, and other printed material relating to her interests in fashion, art, and politics; photographs and photograph albums relating to the Shaw Jones family, Bergery's friendships, and diplomatic travels with Gaston Bergery; biographical material, legal documents, and other personal papers; and a small amount of drawings, other visual materials, and objects. Most materials date from circa 1920s-1990s and concern Bergery's life in Paris, fashion design, and her social circle. Some materials relating to her childhood and family in the United States are also present. Research strengths include 20th-century French fashion design; 20th century European art, literature, and politics; and Gaston Bergery's diplomatic career in Vichy France.
Arrangement
Organized into four groupings: August 2002 Acquisition, August 2002 Acquisition Addition, March 2011 Acquisition, and Other Acquisitions.
Americans -- France -- Paris; Art, French -- 20th Century; Fashion design -- France; Fashion designers -- France; World War, 1939-1945 -- France; World War, 1939-1945 -- Soviet Union; World War, 1939-1945 -- Turkey; Africa, French-speaking Equatorial; Africa, French-speaking Equatorial -- Pictorial works; France -- History -- German occupation, 1940-1945; France -- Politics and government -- 1940-1945; France -- Politics and government -- 1945-1958; Paris (France) -- Intellectual life -- 20th Century; Paris (France) -- Social life and customs -- 20th Century; Soviet Union -- Pictorial works; Turkey -- Pictorial works; Vichy (France) -- Politics and government; Audiovisual materials -- France -- 20th Century; Busts (figures) -- France -- 20th Century; Diaries -- France -- 20th Century; Drawings (visual works) -- France -- 20th Century; Medals -- Italy -- 20th Century; Oil paintings (visual works) -- France -- 20th Century; Phonograph records -- France -- 20th Century; Photograph albums -- France -- 20th Century; Photographs -- France -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- France -- 20th Century; Fashion designers -- France -- 20th Century; Bergery, Bettina, 1902-1993; Bergery, Gaston, 1892-1974; Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963; De Lamar, Alice; Gellhorn, Martha, 1908-1998; Grès, Alix, 1903-1993; John, Pope, XXIII, 1881-1963; La Falaise, Alain de; La Falaise, Loulou de, 1948-2011; La Falaise family; Laure, Marie, 1902-1970; Papen, Franz von, 1879-1969; Schiaparelli, Elsa, 1890-1973; Front populaire; Parti républicain radical et radical-socialiste (France)
- August 2002 Acquisition, circa 1900-circa 1990; 23.76 linear feet (63 boxes) + 1 art
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Mary M. Thacher, 2002.
  Arrangement
  Organized into nine subseries: Correspondence, Diaries, Other Writings by Bettina Bergery, Writings by Others, Printed Material, Personal Papers, Photographs, Visual Materials, and Objects.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence consists mostly of incoming letters from members of Bergery's social circle, with concentrations of letters from Alice De Lamar, Alain de La Falaise, Marie Laure, and Nini von Papen. Also present are letters from her sisters, Anne Jones Fuller and Jean Jones Jackson, as well as other friends from her early life in the United States. Some letters are accompanied by photographs or clippings. Circa 1 linear foot of unsorted and unidentified correspondence likely includes additional letters from individually-listed correspondents.
  Autograph manuscript diaries contain detailed entries about Bergery's social life, travel, and interests in fashion, art and politics. The diaries contain extensive clippings, correspondence, and other material affixed to pages or laid in. Laid-in material has been removed and refoldered separately following each diary. Other writings, autograph manuscript and typescript, include a memoir of a trip to French Equatorial Africa with Gaston Bergery, circa 1936, memoir of an undated visit to the United States, and other autobiographical fragments. Also present are clippings of articles written by Bergery for Vogue, 1950s-1970s.
  Printed material consists mostly of clippings relating to Bergery's interests in fashion, art, and politics. Also present are clippings of British and French newspaper articles about Bettina and Gaston Bergery, 1930s-1940s, criticizing their conduct during World War II, some with autograph manuscript annotations by Bettina Bergery. Other materials include clippings about fashion designer Loulou de La Falaise, and a partly disassembled scrapbook of clippings about fashion designer Alix Grès, with a small amount of related photographs and drawings. Additional clippings are present in the Correspondence and Diaries subseries.
  Personal papers include address and appointment books; passports and other identification papers; and biographical information, obituaries, and papers relating to the deaths of Bettina and Gaston Bergery.
  Photographs are mostly images of Bettina Bergery, dating from childhood through the end of her life, including Shaw Jones family photographs, images of Bergery wearing clothes designed by Elsa Schiaparelli, and images of Bergery with friends. Photographs of Bettina and Gaston Bergery include images of travel in French Equatorial Africa, circa 1936, and photograph albums from Gaston Bergery's diplomatic posts in the Soviet Union and Turkey, 1940s. Many photographs document Bettina Bergery's social circle, with a concentration of images of Alain de La Falaise and other members of the La Falaise family. Additional photographs are present in the Correspondence subseries.
  - Correspondence
    - Barney, Natalie Clifford (Box 1)
    - Beaton, Cecil (Box 1)
    - Beaumont, Etienne de (Box 1)
    - Beistegui, Charles de (Box 1)
    - Bergery, Gaston (Box 1)
    - Bismarck, Mona von, 2 (Box 1)
    - Boll, André (Box 1)
    - Boy, Billy (Box 1)
    - Brooks, Romaine (Box 1)
    - Bryce, Josephine Hartford (Box 1)
    - Castéja, Alexandre, comte de, and Emmeline (Box 1)
    - Cocteau, Jean (Box 1)
    - Croy, Alyette de (Box 1)
    - Dalí, Gala (Box 1)
    - De Lamar, Alice, 4 (Box 1)
    - De Lamar, Alice, 2 (Box 2)
    - Devonshire, Deborah Vivien Freeman-Mitford Cavendish, Duchess of (Box 2)
    - Dubonnet, Ruth (Box 2)
    - Earle, Jacqueline Sacre (Box 2)
    - Fabre-Luce, Alfred (Box 2)
    - Fellowes, Daisy (Box 2)
    - Fitz George, Frank (Box 2)
    - Freuchen, Dagmar (Box 2)
    - Gellhorn, Martha (Box 2)
    - Givenchy, Hubert de (Box 2)
    - Green, Anne (Box 2)
    - Grès, Alix (Box 2)
    - Guyon, Robert (Box 2)
    - Harcourt, Antoinette d' (Box 2)
    - Hart, Evelyn (Box 2)
    - Hart, Gladys (Box 2)
    - Hill, Jerome (Box 2)
    - John XXIII, Pope, 2 (Box 2)
    - Jouvenel, Hélène de, 2 (Box 2)
    - Kochno, Boris (Box 2)
    - Krueger, Malte (Box 3)
    - La Falaise, Alain de, 8 (Box 3)
    - Lahovari, Janine (Box 3)
    - Lanux, Eyre de (Box 3)
    - Laure, Marie, 2 (Box 3)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Noailles, Charles, vicomte de
    - Laure, Marie, 3 (Box 4)
    - Le Selle, Phillip (Box 4)
    - Lord, James (Box 4)
    - Lovett, William Thad (Box 4)
    - Macdonald, Hortense (Box 4)
    - Mapes, John (Box 4)
    - Merlin, Louis (Box 4)
    - Mosley, Diana (Box 4)
    - Munn, Dorothy Spreckels (Box 4)
    - Noailles, Charles, vicomte de (Box 4)
      Includes Laure, Marie
    - Papen, Nini von, 3 (Box 4)
    - Papen, Nini von, 2 (Box 5)
    - Pétain, Philippe (Box 5)
    - Pomereu d'Aligre, Lydie d'Harcourt, comtesse de, 2 (Box 5)
    - Pourtalès, Violette de, comtesse (Box 5)
    - Powel, Gretchen (Box 5)
    - Ralli, Julie Marie ("Figgy") (Box 5)
    - Ristelhueber, Boulos (Box 5)
    - Rubio, Fernando (Box 5)
    - Scapini, Lucie Marie (Box 5)
    - Schiaparelli, Elsa (Box 5)
    - Secrest, Meryle (Box 5)
    - Simpson, Helen (Box 5)
    - Sinnickson, Charles (Box 5)
    - Tackaberry, John (Box 5)
    - Terry, Emilio (Box 5)
    - Thompson, Sylvia (Box 5)
    - Trefusis, Violet (Box 5)
    - Tual, Denise (Box 5)
    - Ullin, Elinor (Box 5)
    - Walter-Guillaume, Domenica (Box 5)
    - Wickes, George (Box 6)
    - Wildman, Frederick S. (Box 6)
    - Unsorted and unidentified, 12 (Box 6)
    - Unsorted and unidentified, 12 folders (Box 7)
    - Unsorted and unidentified, 13 (Box 8)
    - Unsorted and unidentified, 4 (Box 9)
  - Diaries
    - Diary, 1940 September-December (Box 9)
    - Accompanying material, 1940 September-December (Box 9)
    - Diary, 1940 December - 1941 April (Box 9)
    - Accompanying material, 1940 December - 1941 April (Box 9)
    - Diary, 1943 October- 1944 July (Box 9)
    - Diary, 1944 July-December (Box 9)
    - Diary, 1944 December- 1945 April (Box 9)
    - Accompanying material, 1944 December-1945 April (Box 9)
    - Diary, 1945 April-July (Box 9)
    - Diary, 1948 January-April (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1948 January-April (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1948 April-May (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1948 April-May (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1948 May-July (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1948 July-September (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1948 July-September (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1948 November-1949 March (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1948 November-1949 March (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1949 March-June (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1949 March-June (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1949 June-September (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1949 June-September (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1949 September-December (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1949 September-December (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1949 December-1950 March (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1949 December-1950 March (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1950 March-August (Box 10)
    - Accompanying material, 1950 March-August (Box 10)
    - Diary, 1950 August-1951 January (Box 11)
    - Accompanying material, 1950 August-1951 January (Box 11)
    - Diary, 1951 January-June (Box 11)
    - Accompanying material, 1951 January-June (Box 11)
    - Diary, 1951 June-August (Box 11)
    - Diary, 1951 August-November (Box 11)
    - Accompanying material, 1951 August-November (Box 11)
    - Diary, 1951 November-1952 May (Box 11)
    - Accompanying material, 1951 November-1952 May (Box 11)
    - Diary, 1952 May-October (Box 11)
    - Accompanying material, 1952 May-October (Box 11)
    - Diary, 1952 October (Box 11)
    - Accompanying material, 1952 October (Box 11)
    - Diary, 1952 October-1953 March (Box 12)
    - Accompanying material, 1952 October-1953 March (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1953 March-May (Box 12)
    - Accompanying material, 1953 March-May (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1953 May-July (Box 12)
    - Accompanying material, 1953 May-July (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1953 July-October (Box 12)
    - Accompanying material, 1953 July-October (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1953 October-November (Box 12)
    - Accompanying material, 1953 October-November (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1953 November - 1954 January (Box 12)
    - Accompanying material, 1953 November-1954 January (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1954 January-March (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1954 March-May (Box 12)
    - Accompanying material, 1954 March-May (Box 12)
    - Diary, 1954 May-August (Box 13)
    - Accompanying material, 1954 May-August (Box 13)
    - Diary, 1954 August-September (Box 13)
    - Accompanying material, 1954 August-September (Box 13)
    - Diary, 1954 September-November (Box 13)
    - Accompanying material, 1954 September-November (Box 13)
    - Diary, 1954 November-1955 May (Box 13)
    - Accompanying material, 1954 November-1955 May (Box 13)
    - Diary, 1955 May-October (Box 13)
    - Accompanying material, 1955 May-October (Box 13)
    - Diary, 1955 October-1956 January (Box 13)
    - Accompanying material, 1955 October-1956 January (Box 13)
    - Diary, 1956 January-June (Box 13)
    - Accompanying material, 1956 January-June (Box 13)
    - Diary, 1956 June-August (Box 14)
    - Accompanying material, 1956 June-August (Box 14)
    - Diary, 1956 August-September (Box 14)
    - Accompanying material, 1956 August-September (Box 14)
    - Diary, 1956 September-November (Box 14)
    - Accompanying material, 1956 September-November (Box 14)
    - Diary, 1956 November-1957 March (Box 14)
    - Accompanying material, 1956 November-1957 March (Box 14)
    - Diary, 1957 March-April (Box 14)
    - Accompanying material, 1957 March-April (Box 14)
    - Diary, 1957 April-May (Box 14)
    - Accompanying material, 1957 April-May (Box 14)
    - Diary, 1957 May-June (Box 14)
    - Accompanying material, 1957 May-June (Box 14)
    - Diary, 1957 June-July (Box 14)
    - Accompanying material, 1957 June-July (Box 14)
    - Diary, 1957 July-August (Box 15)
    - Accompanying material, 1957 July-August (Box 15)
    - Diary, 1957 August-October (Box 15)
    - Accompanying material, 1957 August-October (Box 15)
    - Diary, 1957 October-1958 February (Box 15)
    - Accompanying material, 1957 October-1958 February (Box 15)
    - Diary, 1958 February-April (Box 15)
    - Accompanying material, 1958 February-April (Box 15)
    - Diary, 1958 April-May (Box 16)
    - Accompanying material, 1958 April-May (Box 16)
    - Diary, 1958 May-June (Box 16)
    - Accompanying material, 1958 May-June (Box 16)
    - Diary, 1958 June-September (Box 16)
    - Accompanying material, 1958 June-September (Box 16)
    - Diary, 1958 September-December (Box 16)
    - Accompanying material, 1958 September-December (Box 16)
    - Diary, 1958 December-1959 April (Box 16)
    - Accompanying material, 1958 December-1959 April; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Diary, 1959 April-July (Box 17)
    - Accompanying material, 1959 April-July; 2 (Box 17)
    - Diary, 1959 August-October (Box 17)
    - Accompanying material, 1959 August-October; 2 (Box 17)
    - Diary, 1959 October-December (Box 18)
    - Accompanying material, 1959 October-December (Box 18)
    - Diary, 1959 December-1960 May (Box 18)
    - Accompanying material, 1959 December-1960 May; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Diary, 1960 May-August (Box 18)
    - Accompanying material, 1960 May-August; 3 (Box 19)
    - Diary, 1960 August-December (Box 19)
    - Accompanying material, 1960 August-December (Box 19)
    - Diary, 1960 December-1961 February (Box 19)
    - Accompanying material, 1960 December-1961 February; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Diary, 1961 February-April (Box 19)
    - Accompanying material, 1961 February-April; 2 (Box 20)
    - Diary, 1961 April-June (Box 20)
    - Accompanying material, 1961 April-June (Box 20)
    - Diary, 1961 June-July (Box 20)
    - Accompanying material, 1961 June-July (Box 20)
    - Diary, 1961 August-September (Box 20)
    - Accompanying material, 1961 August-September (Box 20)
    - Diary, 1961 September-December (Box 20)
    - Accompanying material, 1961 September-December; 3 (Box 21)
    - Diary, 1961 December-1962 January (Box 21)
    - Accompanying material, 1961 December-1962 January (Box 21)
    - Diary, 1962 January-April (Box 21)
    - Accompanying material, 1962 January-April; 4 (Box 22)
    - Diary, 1962 April-May (Box 22)
    - Accompanying material, 1962 April-May (Box 22)
    - Diary, 1962 May-July (Box 22)
    - Accompanying material, 1962 May-July; 2 (Box 22)
    - Diary, 1962 August-September (Box 22)
    - Accompanying material, 1962 August-September (Box 22)
    - Diary, 1962 September-October (Box 23)
    - Accompanying material, 1962 September-October (Box 23)
    - Diary, 1962 October-1963 February (Box 23)
    - Accompanying material, 1962 October-1963 February; 4 folders (Box 23)
    - Diary, 1963 February-May (Box 23)
    - Accompanying material, 1963 February-May; 2 (Box 23)
    - Diary, 1963 April (Box 24)
    - Diary, 1963 May-July (Box 24)
    - Accompanying material, 1963 May-July; 2 (Box 24)
    - Diary, 1963 July-August (Box 24)
    - Accompanying material, 1963 July-August; 2 (Box 24)
    - Diary, 1963 August-November (Box 24)
    - Accompanying material, 1963 August-November; 4 folders (Box 25)
    - Diary, 1963 November-1964 February (Box 25)
    - Accompanying material, 1963 November-1964 February; 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Diary, 1964 February-April (Box 26)
    - Accompanying material, 1964 February-April; 2 (Box 26)
    - Diary, 1964 April-July (Box 26)
    - Accompanying material, 1964 April-July; 2 (Box 26)
    - Diary, 1964 July-August (Box 26)
    - Accompanying material, 1964 July-August; 2 (Box 26)
    - Diary, 1964 August-September (Box 26)
    - Accompanying material, 1964 August-September; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Diary, 1964 October-1965 March (Box 27)
    - Accompanying material, 1964 October-1965 March; 5 folders (Box 27)
    - Diary, 1965 March-June (Box 27)
    - Accompanying material, 1965 March-June; 3 (Box 28)
    - Diary, 1965 June-October (Box 28)
    - Accompanying material, 1965 June-October; 3 (Box 28)
    - Diary, 1965 October-December (Box 28)
    - Accompanying material, 1965 October-December; 2 folders (Box 29)
    - Diary, 1965 December-1966 May (Box 29)
    - Accompanying material, 1965 December-1966 May; 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Diary, 1966 May-July (Box 29)
    - Accompanying material, 1966 May-July; 3 (Box 30)
    - Diary, 1966 August-October (Box 30)
    - Accompanying material, 1966 August-October; 2 (Box 30)
    - Diary, 1966 October-1967 January (Box 30)
    - Accompanying material, 1966 October-1967 January; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Diary, 1967 January-February (Box 30)
    - Accompanying material, 1967 January-February; 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Diary, 1967 February (Box 31)
    - Accompanying material, 1967 February (Box 31)
    - Diary, 1967 February-April (Box 31)
    - Accompanying material, 1967 February-April; 2 (Box 31)
    - Diary, 1967 May-August (Box 31)
    - Accompanying material, 1967 May-August; 6 (Box 31)
    - Diary, 1967 August-September (Box 32)
    - Accompanying material, 1967 August-September; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Diary, 1967 September-November (Box 32)
    - Accompanying material, 1967 September-November; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Diary, 1967 November-1968 August (Box 32)
    - Accompanying material, 1967 November-1968 August; 4 folders (Box 32)
    - Accompanying clippings, 1968 spring, 1967 November-1968 August; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Accompanying clippings, 1968 spring, 1967 November-1968 August; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Diary, 1968 May-July (Box 33)
    - Accompanying material, 1968 May-July; 2 (Box 33)
    - Diary, 1968 August-September (Box 33)
    - Accompanying material, 1968 August-September (Box 33)
    - Diary, 1968 November-1969 January (Box 33)
    - Accompanying material, 1968 November-1969 January; 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Diary, 1969 January-April (Box 33)
    - Accompanying material, 1969 January-April; 3 (Box 33)
    - Diary, 1969 May-July (Box 34)
    - Accompanying material, 1969 May-July; 2 (Box 34)
    - Diary, 1969 July-December (Box 34)
    - Accompanying material, 1969 July-December; 3 (Box 34)
    - Diary, 1969 December-1970 March (Box 34)
    - Accompanying material, 1969 December-1970 March; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Diary, 1970 March-August (Box 35)
    - Accompanying material, 1970 March-August (Box 35)
    - Diary, 1970 August-November (Box 35)
    - Accompanying material, 1970 August-November; 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Diary, 1970 November-1971 January (Box 35)
    - Accompanying material, 1970 November-1971 January (Box 35)
    - Diary, 1971 January-May (Box 35)
    - Accompanying material, 1971 January-May (Box 35)
    - Diary, 1971 May-October (Box 35)
    - Accompanying material, 1971 May-October (Box 36)
    - Diary, 1971 October-1972 February (Box 36)
    - Accompanying material, 1971 October-1972 February (Box 36)
    - Diary, 1972 February-June (Box 36)
    - Accompanying material, 1972 February-June (Box 36)
    - Diary, 1972 July-1973 May (Box 36)
    - Accompanying material, 1972 July-1973 May (Box 36)
    - Diary, 1973 May-October (Box 36)
    - Accompanying material, 1973 May-October (Box 36)
    - Diary, 1973 October-1974 January (Box 37)
    - Accompanying material, 1973 October-1974 January (Box 37)
    - Diary, 1974 January-July (Box 37)
    - Accompanying material, 1974 January-July (Box 37)
    - Diary, 1974 July-September (Box 37)
    - Accompanying material, 1974 July-September (Box 37)
    - Diary, 1974 September-October (Box 37)
    - Accompanying material, 1974 September-October (Box 37)
    - Diary, 1978 November-1979 January (Box 37)
    - Accompanying material, 1978 November-1979 January (Box 37)
    - Diary, 1979 May-November (Box 37)
    - Accompanying material, 1979 May-November (Box 37)
    - Diary, 1980 January-April (Box 38)
    - Accompanying material, 1980 January-April; 3 (Box 38)
  - Other Writings by Bettina Bergery
    - Fashion design notes, 2 (Box 38)
    - Fashion sketches (Box 38)
    - "The Return of the Native (With Apologies...)" (Box 38)
      About a trip to New York City, Florida, and Stonington, Connecticut
    - Unidentified, 5 (Box 38)
    - Unidentified, 5 (Box 39)
  - Writings by Others
    - Balsan, Natalie. Gaston Bergery, 5 (Box 39)
    - Bergery, Gaston. Pamphlets about the Parti frontiste (Box 39)
    - de Lamar, Alice. Memoir about the Spence School (Box 39)